<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Hassan Saei</title>
    <link>https://hassansaei.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Hassan Saei</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2024 Hassan Saei</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hassansaei.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Splice modulation therapy development using XLAS organoid models</title>
      <link>https://hassansaei.github.io/project/organoid_aso/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hassansaei.github.io/project/organoid_aso/</guid>
      <description>Kidney organoids are an emerging tool for disease modeling, especially genetic diseases. Among these diseases, X-linked Alport syndrome (XLAS) is a hematuric nephropathy affecting the glomerular basement membrane (GBM) secondary to pathogenic variations in the COL4A5 gene encoding the α5 subunit of type IV collagen [α5(IV)]. In patients carrying pathogenic variations affecting splicing, the use of antisense oligonucleotides (ASOs) offers immense therapeutic hope. In this study, we develop a framework combining the use of patient-derived cells and kidney organoids to provide evidence of the therapeutic efficacy of ASOs in XLAS patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WIDGeT consortium project</title>
      <link>https://hassansaei.github.io/project/widget/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hassansaei.github.io/project/widget/</guid>
      <description>The WIDGeT consortium (Viral Vector Intelligent Design for Gene Therapy) aims to accelerate the development of gene therapies using viral vectors derived from adeno-associated viruses (AAV) for the treatment of age-related macular degeneration (AMD) and hereditary podocytopathies (kidney diseases), leveraging the potential of artificial intelligence (AI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A tool to genotype coding VNTR in ADTKD-MUC1</title>
      <link>https://hassansaei.github.io/project/adtkd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hassansaei.github.io/project/adtkd/</guid>
      <description>Autosomal dominant tubulointerstitial kidney disease (ADTKD) is a hereditary condition characterized by progressive tubulointerstitial fibrosis with or without tubular dilation and atrophy, eventually leading to end-stage kidney failure. The affected individuals present mild to negative proteinuria, and bland urinary sediment abnormalities, with normal kidney size. A positive family history is commonly reported for this disease. Molecular genetics play a key role in diagnosing and classifying ADTKD given their non-specific presentations. Pathogenic variants in different genes, including MUC1, UMOD, HNF1B, REN, and SEC61A1, are known to be responsible for ADTKD.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>